Guide to the Godzilla Asian American Arts Network Archive 1990-2003 MSS.166
Fales Library and Special Collections
Godzilla Asian American Arts Network Archive
1990-2003
Fales Library and Special Collections
Godzilla Asian American Arts Network
MSS.166
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Godzilla Asian American Arts Network Archive houses the materials of the Godzilla Asian American Arts Network. The collection includes correspondence, exhibition dossiers, administrative materials, publications, and related materials.
Provenance
Ken Chu, founder of the Godzilla: Asian American Arts Network, donated the materials to the Fales Library in 2005.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Historical Note
Godzilla was an Asian American arts collective and support network founded in 1990. Godzilla's founding members believed that Asian American artists did not have a suitable organization to support, promote, and encourage their visual arts, and Godzilla sought to fill this need. Godzilla disbanded in 2001.
Scope and Content Note
The Godzilla Asian American Arts Network Archive contains documents relating to the activities and goals of the Godzilla Asian American Arts Network. Included are documents detailing the administrative and artistic aspects of Godzilla and related arts organizations.
Arrangement
The Godzilla Asian American Arts Network Archive has been arranged into five series: Correspondence, Exhibitions, Newsletters and Publicity, Administrative Materials, and Related Organizations.
Where applicable, the folders within the five series have been arranged chronologically. The contents of the folders are also arranged by date unless otherwise organized by Godzilla.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Exhibitions
Series III: Newsletters and Publicity
Series IV: Administrative Materials
Series V: Related Organizations
OVERSIZE Series II: Exhibitions
OVERSIZE Series V: Related Organizations
Photographs.; Correspondence.; Multiculturalism.; Clippings (information artifacts); Periodicals; Art |x Finance.; New York (N.Y.).; Art and society.; Notes.; Grant proposals.; Racism.; Slides (photographs); Fliers (printed matter); Asian American artists.; Asian American arts |z New York (State) |z New York.; Asian American arts |z New York (State) |z New York |v Periodicals.; Asian Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Artists and community -- United States; Asian American art |y 20th century |v Exhibitions.; Asian American art |y 21st century |v Exhibitions.; Asian American art -- Periodicals.; Asian American artists |v Exhibitions.; Financial records; Asian American artists |z New York (State) |z New York |v Exhibitions.; Asian American artists |z New York (State) |z New York |v Societies.; Asian American artists |z United States |v Periodicals.; Art |x Finance |z United States; Godzilla Asian American Arts Network; Yamamoto, Lynne, 1961-; Asian American Arts Alliance; Chu, Ken; Godzilla (Group of artists) -- Exhibitions
- Series I: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains Godzilla's correspondence from 1991-2001, as well as letters to send to artists and files kept by Lynne Yamamoto and Godzilla founder Ken Chu. Ken Chu's folders contain notices of upcoming art exhibitions sent to him by artitsts, two slides of his own work, and a newspaper clipping. Lynne Yamamoto's folder, separated into two parts, holds correspondence and administrative documents she collected.
  - Correspondence 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1995, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Undated Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Godzilla artists regarding From Basement to Godzilla, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence sent to Ken Chu, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Dan Gilbert to Ken Chu, enclosing two slides of Chu's artwork, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clipping of Off-Campus newspaper collected by Chu, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence collected by Lynne Yamamoto, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10 A)
  - Godzilla administrative documents collected by Lynne Yamamoto, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10 B)
- Series II: Exhibitions
  This series contains dossiers from Godzilla's various exhibitions, including photographs, brochures, and logistical documents. Nine exhibitions are included, as well as miscellaneous photographs.
  - New World Order III: The Curio Shop Exhibition Dossier, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Word Gets Around Project Materials, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles...Not! and Reed Arts Weekend Documents, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles...Not! Exibition Dossier, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - And We Speak Exhibition Dossier, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Travel-Sized Exhibition Dossier, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Bank/Why Are You Here? Exhibition Documents, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fermented Exhibition Documents, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Art in General:Why Asia? Exhibition Documents, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Gallery Submission Guidelines, various (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series III: Newsletters and Publicity
  Series III comprises the Godzilla newsletter and publishing information as well as the "Godzillette" bulletin, an issue of New Observations magazine edited by Godzilla, and Godzilla events fliers.
  - Godzilla Newsletters and Publication Information, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Godzillettes", 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - New Observations Magazine #107 (Guest Editor: Godzilla), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Godzilla Events Fliers, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series IV: Administrative Materials
  Series IV contains administrative materials broken down into two subseries: organizational documents and financial documents. Subseries A: Organizational Documents has introductory and operations information, contact sheets, steering committee minutes and other administrative documents such as a questionnaire and Godzilla stationary. Suberies B: Financial Documents holds Godzilla's financial records from 1991-2003, along with grant applications and miscellaneous/undated financial records and other document fragments.
  - Subseries A: Organizational Documents
    - Godzilla Introduction and Operations Information, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Godzilla Contact Sheets, various (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Steering Committee Minutes, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Godzilla Spring 1994 Questionnaire (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Godzilla Stationary, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Subseries B: Financial Documents
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1995 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1996 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 1999 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 2000 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 2001 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 2002 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Godzilla Financial Records 2003 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous Godzilla Financial Records, various (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Godzilla Grant Materials, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - North Star Fund Materials, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Series V: Related Organizations
  Series V comprises various documents, articles, and publications either published by or related to organizations related to Godzilla. Some organizations, such as the Asian American Arts Alliance, collaborated with Godzilla; others simply had a similar purpose. Series V contains three subseries: Documents, Publications, and Items of Interest to Godzilla. Series A: Documents houses ideas for collaboratory projects, financial information, and operating information about related organizations. Subseries B: Publications contains journals, newsletters, and exhibition brochures from similar arts organizations. Subseries C: Items of Interest to Godzilla holds newspaper clippings and articles collected by Godzilla that either feature Godzilla and/or a related organization, or address a cause related to Godzilla's purpose.
  - Subseries A: Documents from Related Organizations
    - Collaboratory Proposals, various (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Documents from Related Organizations, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Asian American Arts Alliance Financial Documents, 1993, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Subseries B: Publications
    - Asian American Arts Alliance Publications, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Publications of Related Organizations, 1986-1998 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Exhibit Brochures, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Subseries C: Items of Interest to Godzilla
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Articles of Interest Collected by Godzilla, various (Box 1, Folder 55)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Exhibitions
  Series II OVERSIZE houses a collector's set of prints from the From Basement to Godzilla exhibition.
  - From Basement to Godzilla Exhibition Prints, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Related Organizations
  - Subseries B: Publications
    - Gidra Magazine 20th Anniversary Edition, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 57)